<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://iamprashant.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://iamprashant.in/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-02-29T05:11:47+05:30</updated><id>http://iamprashant.in/</id><title>Prashant&#39;s Blog</title><subtitle>Technical blog, technical writing, developer says, programmer throught, thinking , development, programming </subtitle><entry><title>First article so will started with ‘Hello world’</title><link href="http://iamprashant.in/2016/02/28/first-post-hello/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First article so will started with &#39;Hello world&#39;" /><published>2016-02-28T17:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-02-28T17:30:00+05:30</updated><id>http://iamprashant.in/2016/02/28/first-post-hello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://iamprashant.in/2016/02/28/first-post-hello/">&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;strong&gt;Prashant Srivastav&lt;/strong&gt; as blog url says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m working as Software engineer at Koove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I’m passionate about working in Information technology and Research.
I love to do research about new ideas and find new ways to implement them in different ways&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Worked in Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i started printing &quot;Hello World&quot; in C using printf while learning and exploring c in my college days because this is first and simple program which is given in book or first example given by teacher. But printing &quot;Hello World&quot; used as a greeting or to begin a program in computer language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&#39;ve worked in various technologies and language. when i started coding while graduation my favourite language was &lt;strong&gt;.NET&lt;/strong&gt; then i started exploring Java and PHP to develop and Java Script and Angularjs to design. now i&#39;m exploring android with rxjava to improve and manage code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to work in linux/unix environment. As techOps i have worked and used physical servers for hosting, managing and monitoing  of application and servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting thing is while writing this blog i&#39;ve started exploring &lt;strong&gt;Ruby&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;jekyll&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;when you don&#39;t create things, you become defined by your tastes rather than ability. your tastes only narrow &amp;amp; exclude people. so create.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &quot;Hello World&quot; to start, somtimes writing &quot;Hello World&quot; also becomes difficult.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Prashant Srivastav</name></author><summary>I am Prashant Srivastav as blog url says.</summary></entry></feed>
